[{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408b679c515c23447160ca8"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "The word Hindu originated from",
  "correct_answer": "Paramashiva himself. He defines \"Hindu\" as whole, those who defeats the evils.",
  "answers": [
    "The Persians who designated the land beyond the river Sindhu as Hindu and people living there as Hindus",
    "The britishers who misspelt the river name Sindhu as Hindu and named all people who lived beyond this river as Hindu",
    "Paramashiva himself. He defines \"Hindu\" as whole, those who defeats the evils.",
    "People of India themself started calling as Hindus to get a identity"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408b9f0c515c23447160ca9"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Agamas consists of four parts. They are",
  "correct_answer": "Charya pada, Kriya pada, Yoga pada, Jnana pada",
  "answers": [
    "Karma yoga, Bhakti yoga, Raja yoga and Jnana yoga",
    "Charya pada, Kriya pada, Yoga pada, Jnana pada",
    "Salokya, Sarupya, Sayujya, Samipya"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408bc98c515c23447160caa"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Which are the three origins of human beings",
  "correct_answer": "Surya Vamsa, Chandra Vamsa & Agni Vamsha",
  "answers": [
    "Surya Vamsa, Chandra Vamsa & Agni Vamsha",
    "Surya Vamsa, Chandra Vamsa & Vayu Vamsha",
    "Surya Vamsa, Chandra Vamsa & Varuna Vamsha",
    "Surya Vamsa, Chandra Vamsa & Vaivasvata Vamsha"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408bd11c515c23447160cab"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who was the King of Bhramavarta",
  "correct_answer": "Swayambhava Manu",
  "answers": [
    "Swayambhava Manu",
    "Pulaha",
    "Pulastya",
    "Angirasa"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408bd62c515c23447160cac"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Was Kingdom of Bharata descendents of Manu dynasty",
  "correct_answer": "Yes",
  "answers": [
    "No",
    "Yes"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408bdc4c515c23447160cad"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Kingdom of Ayodhya was founded by",
  "correct_answer": "King Manu & his wife Ida",
  "answers": [
    "King Dasharatha",
    "King Manu & his wife Ida",
    "King Bharata",
    "King Aja"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408be4ec515c23447160cae"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Why does Pandya Kingdom has 2 fishes as their emblem",
  "correct_answer": "Vishnu took Matsyavatara twice. First to get the Vedas and Agamas and second to pull the boat of Manu",
  "answers": [
    "They believed evolution started from fish",
    "Vishnu took Matsyavatara twice. First to get the Vedas and Agamas and second to pull the boat of Manu",
    "Main economy of Pandya kingdom was by trading fish",
    "None of the above"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408bef3c515c23447160caf"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who all held the title Manu",
  "correct_answer": "King Satvavrata and Swayambhuva",
  "answers": [
    "King Satvavrata and Swayambhuva",
    "Ikshvaku",
    "Trisanku"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408bfc0c515c23447160cb0"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Masyavarata (Vishnu) pulled the ship having Manu and landed near",
  "correct_answer": "Kanyakumari",
  "answers": [
    "Sri Lankha",
    "Kanyakumari",
    "Dwaraka",
    "Orissa"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c024c515c23447160cb1"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who was the first person who created constitution based on Vedic Tradition",
  "correct_answer": "Manu",
  "answers": [
    "Vishwamitra",
    "Rama",
    "Manu",
    "Paramashiva himself"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c08bc515c23447160cb2"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Is Pandya dynasty older than Mesapatomian and Egyptian civilization?",
  "correct_answer": "Yes",
  "answers": [
    "No",
    "Yes"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c0f9c515c23447160cb3"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "During coronation, Minaksi took oath on",
  "correct_answer": "Manu Dharma Sastras",
  "answers": [
    "Vedas & Agamas",
    "Manu Dharma Sastras",
    "Bhagavatgeeta",
    "Upanishads"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c146c515c23447160cb4"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who created the world first democratic governance structure",
  "correct_answer": "Manu",
  "answers": [
    "British",
    "Basavanna",
    "Manu",
    "Rama"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c199c515c23447160cb5"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Ikshvaku was son of ",
  "correct_answer": "Vaivasvata Manu",
  "answers": [
    "Harishchandra",
    "Vaivasvata Manu",
    "Bharata",
    "Bagiratha"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c1ddc515c23447160cb6"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "First work on Ayurveda was started by",
  "correct_answer": "Agnivesa",
  "answers": [
    "Dhanvantri",
    "Kasyapa",
    "Agnivesa",
    "Charaka"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c20dc515c23447160cb7"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Kingdom of Kashi was build by",
  "correct_answer": "Swayambhava Manu",
  "answers": [
    "King Kshatraviddha",
    "Lord Mahakal",
    "Lord Paramashiva",
    "King Janaka"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c25fc515c23447160cb8"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Out of 5 jyotir lingas, the prithvi linga which Devi Parashakti herself created is in",
  "correct_answer": "Ekambaranathar temple",
  "answers": [
    "Chidambara temple",
    "Ekambaranathar temple",
    "Kalahasti temple",
    "Jambukeshwarar temple"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c2b1c515c23447160cb9"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who built the Kanchi Kamakshi Amman temple",
  "correct_answer": "Tondaiman",
  "answers": [
    "Tondaiman",
    "Mahendravarman 1",
    "Shima Vishnu",
    "Aditya 1"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c31dc515c23447160cba"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "One of the 6 sat-darshana tattva - Nyaya Sutras originated from",
  "correct_answer": "Risi Goutama",
  "answers": [
    "Risi Goutama",
    "Kapila",
    "Vyasa",
    "Jaimini"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c3c0c515c23447160cbb"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who is a founding father of Mahanirvani Akhada",
  "correct_answer": "Kapila",
  "answers": [
    "Marichi",
    "Kapila",
    "Lord Ganesha",
    "Agastya"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c427c515c23447160cbc"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Who revealed Sankya sutras",
  "correct_answer": "Kapila Muni",
  "answers": [
    "Sri Krishna",
    "Kapila Muni",
    "Atri",
    "Kashyapa"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c46ec515c23447160cbd"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Brahma sutras was revealed by",
  "correct_answer": "Badarayana Vyasa",
  "answers": [
    "Lord Brahma",
    "Badarayana Vyasa",
    "Vamana",
    "Vishwamitra"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c4b0c515c23447160cbe"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "The earliest astronomical text - SuryaSiddhanta was authored by",
  "correct_answer": "Mayasura",
  "answers": [
    "Varahamihira",
    "Mayasura",
    "Vashista",
    "Aryabhatta"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c503c515c23447160cbf"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "Which are the three origins of human beings",
  "correct_answer": "Rama",
  "answers": [
    "Vamana",
    "Matsyavatara",
    "Varaha",
    "Rama"
  ]
},{
  "_id": {
    "$oid": "6408c561c515c23447160cc0"
  },
  "category": "hindu_history",
  "type": "mcq",
  "difficulty": "medium",
  "question": "During the Mahabharata war, which side did Malayadhvaja Pandya side with",
  "correct_answer": "He took side of Pandavas",
  "answers": [
    "He was not involved in the Mahabharata war",
    "He took side of Kauravas",
    "He took side of Pandavas",
    "He was involved in Mahabharata war, but did not side with anyone. He just offered help to the wounded irrespective"
  ]
}]